{
  "edition": "Default",
  "version": "1",
  "units": [
    {
      "unitName": "Discrete Mathematics",
      "chapters": [
        {
          "topic": "Binomial Theorem",
          "lesson": "In elementary algebra, the binomial theorem (or binomial expansion) describes the algebraic expansion of powers of a binomial. According to the theorem, it is possible to expand the polynomial \\( (x + y)^n \\) into a sum involving terms of the form \\( ax^b y^c \\), where the exponents b and c are nonnegative integers with b + c = n, and the coefficient a of each term is a specific positive integer depending on n and b. For example,\n $$ (x+y)^{4}=x^{4}+4x^{3}y+6x^{2}y^{2}+4xy^{3}+y^{4}.$$ \nThe coefficient a in the term of \\( ax^b y^c \\) is known as the binomial coefficient \\( \\binom {n}{b} \\) or \\( \\binom {n}{c} \\) (the two have the same value). These coefficients for varying n and b can be arranged to form Pascal's triangle. These numbers also arise in combinatorics, where \\( \\binom {n}{b} \\) gives the number of different combinations of b elements that can be chosen from an n-element set.\n Sources: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Binomial_theorem",
          "questions": [
            {
              "question": "5 people became friends at a Summer Camp. On the last day, they shook each other's hands to say farewell. How many handshakes were there?",
              "options": [
                "5",
                "10",
                "25",
                "6"
              ],
              "answer": "10",
              "solution": "Answer: 10\n    \n    Solution 1: Let's count it slowly, by per person. \n    The first person has 4 other hands to shake. Now let's ignore the first person. \n    The second person has 3 other hands to shake (excluding the first person). Now let's ignore the second person. \n    The third person has 2 other hands to shake (excluding the first and second person). Now let's ignore the third person. \n    The fourth person has 1 other hands to shake (excluding the first, second and third person). This is all that remains.\n    \n    Hence, there are  \\( 4 + 3 + 2 + 1 = 10 \\) handshakes that occurred.\n    \n    Solution 2: We can draw a graph to represent this. There are 5 vertices representing each of the students. Between each vertex, we draw an edge to represent a handshake. We can count that there are 10 edges, hence there are 10 handshakes that occurred."
            },
            {
              "question": "What positive integer \\(n\\) satisfies\n \\[{{n+2} \\choose 7}=41 \\cdot {n \\choose 5}?\\]",
              "options": [
                "108",
                "41",
                "40",
                "0"
              ],
              "answer": "40",
              "solution": "Answer: 40\n    \n    Observe that the equation can be rewritten as\n\n     \\[{{n+2} \\choose 7} =41 \\cdot {n \\choose 5} \\ \\frac{(n+2)(n+1)n(n-1)}{7!} =41 \times \frac{n(n-1)}{5!}.\\]\n    \n    Since  \\(n\\) is positive, dividing both sides of this by  \\(n(n-1)\\) gives\n     \\[(n+2)(n+1) =42 \\cdot 41.\\]\n\n    This is satisfied for  \\(n=40\\)."
            },
            {
              "question": "Binomial Theorem Expansions\n    \n    For what value of  \\(N\\), is the following an algebraic identity:\n\n     \\[ (x+y)^N = x^4 + 4 x^3 y + 6 x^2y^2 + 4 xy^3 + y^4? \\]",
              "options": [
                "1",
                "2",
                "3",
                "4"
              ],
              "answer": "4",
              "solution": "Answer: 4\n     \n     By the binomial theorem, we know that\n\n     \\[ (x+y)^4 = = x^4 + 4 x^3 y + 6 x^2y^2 + 4 xy^3 + y^4. \\]"
            },
            {
              "question": "Binomial Theorem challenge:\n     \n      \\[\n      \\sum_{ r=0 }^{ n } { (-1 )}^{ r } {{n}\\choose{r}}^{-1} \\]\n      \n      If  \\(n\\) is an an odd positive integer, find the value of this sum.",
              "options": [
                "-1",
                "0",
                "1",
                "null"
              ],
              "answer": "0",
              "solution": "Answer: 0\n     \n     Recall that  \\({{n}\\choose{r}} = {{n}\\choose{n - r}}.\\) Since  \\(n\\) is odd,  \\(n-r\\) has the opposite parity as  \\(r,\\) so\n\n     \\[{(-1)^r} {{{n}\\choose{r}}^{-1}} = -(-1)^{n-r}{{n}\\choose{n-r}}^{-1}.\\]\n    \n    Thus, when we pair the terms in this way, each pair sums to 0, so the summation is 0."
            },
            {
              "question": "Binomial Theorem Challenge 2:\n    \n     \\[\n      \\sum_{k=0}^n  (-1)^k {{n}\\choose{k}} (n-k)^n = ?\\]\n",
              "options": [
                "n!",
                "1",
                "(n-1)!",
                "0"
              ],
              "answer": "n!",
              "solution": "Answer: n!\n    \n    In a bijective, number of elements in domain = number of elements of co-domain = (n) and range is equal to co-domain.\n    \n    In a bijective, No. of one-one functions is equal to number of onto functions.\n    \n    No.of. onto functions =  \\(\\sum_{k=0}^n(-1)^k{{n}\\choose{n-k}}^m\\).\n    \n    Here, m = n.\n    \n    So,  \\(\\sum_{k=0}^n(-1)^k{{n}\\choose{n-k}}^n\\) = number of one-one functions from n to n = n!.\n"
            },
            {
              "question": "Binomial Theorem Challenge 3:\n    \n    Find the number of odd coefficients in the expansion of  \\( (a + b)^{2015} \\).",
              "options": [
                "512",
                "1024",
                "2048",
                "2047"
              ],
              "answer": "1024",
              "solution": "Answer: 1024\n    \n    We will make use of a consequence of Lucas' Theorem, whereby a binomial coefficient  \\({{m}\\choose{n}}\\) is odd if and only if none of the digits in the binary expansion of  \\(n\\) is greater than the corresponding digit in the binary expansion of  \\(m.\\)\n\n    In this case we have  \\(m = 2015,\\) which has a binary of 11111011111.\n    \n    So all those binomial coefficients  \\({{2015}\\choose{n}}\\) in the expansion of  \\((a + b)^{2015}\\) for which  \\(n\\) does not have a  \\(1\\) in the  \\(6\\)th from the right digit in their binary expansion will be odd. \n    \n    Since all numbers from  \\(2016\\) to  \\(2047\\) do have a  \\(1\\) in this position, we can then conclude that\n    the number of values \\(n\\) from \\(0\\) to \\(2015\\) inclusive that do not have a  \\(1\\) in this position will be  \\(\frac{2048}{2} = 1024.\\)"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "topic": "Rule of Sum and Product",
          "lesson": "In combinatorics, the rule of sum or addition principle is a basic counting principle. Stated simply, it is the idea that if we have a ways of doing something and b ways of doing another thing and we can not do both at the same time, then there are a + b ways to choose one of the actions.\n More formally, the rule of sum is a fact about set theory. It states that sum of the sizes of a finite collection of pairwise disjoint sets is the size of the union of these sets. That is, if \\( S_{1},S_{2},...,S_{n} \\) are pairwise disjoint sets, then we have: \n $$ |S_{1}|+|S_{2}|+\\cdots +|S_{n}|=|S_{1}\\cup S_{2}\\cup \\cdots \\cup S_{n}| $$ \n In combinatorics, the rule of product or multiplication principle is a basic counting principle (a.k.a. the fundamental principle of counting). Stated simply, it is the idea that if there are a ways of doing something and b ways of doing another thing, then there are a · b ways of performing both actions.\n Sources: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rule_of_sum\nhttps://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rule_of_product",
          "questions": [
            {
              "question": "A university has three parking lots, call it A, B, and C.  Lot A has 80 spaces, lot B has 90 spaces, and lot C has 310 spaces.  If a car comes to the university, how many choices are there for the car to park in the parking space?",
              "options": [
                "480",
                "310",
                "300",
                "uncountable"
              ],
              "answer": "480",
              "solution": "Answer: 480"
            },
            {
              "question": "\\item How many triples of positive integers \\( (a, b, c) \\) are there such that\n    \n    \\[\\frac{a^2 + b^2}{c}, \\quad <4a\\le 5, \\quad b\\le 5, \\quad c\\le 5? \\]",
              "options": [
                "19",
                "24",
                "29",
                "34"
              ],
              "answer": "29",
              "solution": "Answer: 29\n    \n    Since all of  \\(a, b\\) and  \\(c\\) are positive integers between  \\(1\\) and  \\(5,\\) inclusive, we check each of the options as follows:\n\nIf  \\( c = 5, \\) then  \\((a, b)=(4,1)\\) or  \\((3,3)\\) or  \\((3,2)\\) or  \\((3,1)\\) or  \\((2,3)\\) or  \\((2,2)\\) or  \\((2, 1)\\) or  \\((1,4)\\) or  \\((1, 3)\\) or  \\((1, 2)\\) or  \\((1, 1),\\) which gives  \\(11\\) solutions.\n\nIf  \\( c = 4, \\) then  \\((a, b)=(3,2)\\) or  \\((3,1)\\) or  \\((2,3)\\) or  \\((2,2)\\) or  \\((2, 1)\\) or  \\((1, 3)\\) or  \\((1, 2)\\) or  \\((1, 1),\\) which gives  \\(8\\) solutions.\n\nIf  \\( c = 3, \\) then  \\((a, b)=(3,1)\\) or  \\((2,2)\\) or  \\((2, 1)\\) or  \\((1, 3)\\) or  \\((1, 2)\\) or  \\((1, 1),\\) which gives  \\(6\\) solutions.\n\nIf  \\( c = 2, \\) then  \\((a, b)=(2, 1)\\) or  \\((1, 2)\\) or  \\((1, 1),\\) which gives  \\(3\\) solutions.\n\nIf  \\( c = 1, \\) then  \\((a, b)=(1, 1),\\) which gives  \\(1\\) solution.\n\nHence, there are  \\(11+8+6+3+1=29\\) solutions altogether."
            },
            {
              "question": "\n    While training for the Olympics, Sebastian as to swim, then cycle, and then run.  To practice, he can either 200, 300, 400, or 500 meters, then cycle for 5, 8, 13, or 21 kilometers, and finally run for either 2 or 3 kilometers.  How many possible choices of training does Sebastian have?",
              "options": [
                "1",
                "3",
                "10",
                "32"
              ],
              "answer": "32",
              "solution": "Answer:\n    32\n    \n    Since Trina will be doing each activity, we use the rule of product. So Sebastian will have \\(4 \times 4 \times 2 = 32\\) possible choices for her training."
            },
            {
              "question": "In Alice's closet, there are 4 different pants, 9 different shirts and n different jackets. If the number of combinations of pants, shirts and jackets Alice can choose is 252 how many different jackets does she have?",
              "options": [
                "7",
                "9",
                "13",
                "239"
              ],
              "answer": "7",
              "solution": "Answer: 7\n    For each of the  \\(n\\) different jackets, there are  \\(4\\) different pants and  \\(9\\) different shirts to choose from. Thus, the total number of combinations is  \\(4 \times 9 \times n,\\) implying\n\n \\[4 \times 9 \times n & = 252 \\]\n \\[n = 7 \\]\n\nThus, Alice has  \\(7\\) different jackets."
            },
            {
              "question": "Find the number of 2 digit numbers whose digit sum is a perfect square.",
              "options": [
                "5",
                "14",
                "20",
                "17"
              ],
              "answer": "17",
              "solution": "Answer: 17\n    \n    Let  \\(n=10a+b\\). We have that  \\(1<=a<=9\\) and  \\(0<=b<=9\\), so  \\(0<=a+b<=18\\). The perfect squares for that range is  \\(1,4,9 \\) and  \\(16\\). For the case  \\(1\\),  \\(10\\) is unique because you can't raise  \\(b\\) and lower  \\(a\\) and  \\(a+b\\) remain as  \\(1\\). For the case  \\(4\\) the higher value is  \\(40\\), so we have  \\(4\\) possibilities because  \\(1<=a<=4\\). For the case  \\(9\\),  \\(90\\) is the higher value,  \\(1<=a<=9\\) so we have  \\(9\\) possibilities. Finally, for the case  \\(16\\),  \\(97\\) is the higher value, as we lower  \\(a\\) and raise  \\(b\\) we will have only  \\(3\\) possibilities because  \\(b\\) already started at  \\(7\\). Summing all possibilities:  \\(1+4+9+3=17\\)."
            },
            {
              "question": "If you take a  \\(3 \\times 3 \\times 3\\) Rubik cube and break it up into the  \\( 3^3 \\) cubes, how many cubes would have stickers on exactly  \\(2\\) faces?",
              "options": [
                "6",
                "8",
                "12",
                "26"
              ],
              "answer": "12",
              "solution": "Answer: 12\n    \n    Typical Rubik's cube ($3 \times 3 \times 3$) has 8 corners and 12 sides.  There is only one cube in between the two corner cubes at each side. This yields the number of cubes having sticker on two side be  \\(12\times1 =\boxed{12}\\)."
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "topic": "Set Theory",
          "lesson": "Set theory is a branch of mathematical logic that studies sets, which informally are collections of objects. Although any type of object can be collected into a set, set theory is applied most often to objects that are relevant to mathematics. The language of set theory can be used in the definitions of nearly all mathematical objects.\nThe modern study of set theory was initiated by Georg Cantor and Richard Dedekind in the 1870s. After the discovery of paradoxes in naive set theory, such as the Russell's paradox, numerous axiom systems were proposed in the early twentieth century, of which the Zermelo–Fraenkel axioms, with the axiom of choice, are the best-known.\nSet theory is commonly employed as a foundational system for mathematics, particularly in the form of Zermelo–Fraenkel set theory with the axiom of choice. Beyond its foundational role, set theory is a branch of mathematics in its own right, with an active research community. Contemporary research into set theory includes a diverse collection of topics, ranging from the structure of the real number line to the study of the consistency of large cardinals.\n Sources: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Set_theory",
          "questions": [
            {
              "question": "Given the sets \\(A = \\{2, 20, 22, 5, 13\\}\\) and \\(B = \\{6, 9, 20, 12, 22\\}\\), what is the sum of all the elements in \\(A \\cup B\\)?",
              "options": [
                "89",
                "131",
                "42",
                "98"
              ],
              "answer": "89",
              "solution": "Answer: 89\n    \n     \\(A \\cup B\\) is the set of elements in  \\(A\\) or  \\(B\\). So we have  \\(A \\cup B = A + B - A \\cap B\\), where  \\(A \\cap B = \\{20, 22\\}\\). Thus  \\(A \\cup B = \\{2, 5, 6, 9, 12, 13, 20, 22 \\}\\). Hence the sum is  \\(2 + 5 + 6 + 9 + 12 + 13 + 20 + 22 = 89\\)."
            },
            {
              "question": "Symmetric Difference\n     \\[\n     A =\\{x \\mid -8 < x < 4, x \\text{ is an integer} \\},\n     \\]\n     \\[\n     B =\\{x \\mid -2 < x \\leq 11, x \\text{ is an integer} \\}.\\]\nWhat is  \\( \\lvert A \\triangle B \\rvert \\), the size of the symmetric difference of A and B?",
              "options": [
                "13",
                "11",
                "14",
                "9"
              ],
              "answer": "14",
              "solution": "Answer: 14\n     \n     Observe that  \\(A \\cup B\\) is the set of integers  \\(x\\) satisfying  \\( - 8 < x \\leq 11\\) and  \\(A \\cap B\\) is the set of integers  \\(x\\) satisfying  \\(-2 < x < 4.\\) This implies\n \\[\begin{aligned} A \triangle B &= (A \\cup B)-(A \\cap B) \\ &= \\{x \\mid -8 < x \\leq -2, \text{ or } 4 \\leq x \\leq 11, x \text{ is an integer} \\}. \\end{aligned} \\]\nThus, the number of elements in the set  \\(A \triangle B\\) is\n \\[ \\lvert A \triangle B \rvert = (-2-(-8))+(11-4+1)=14.\\]"
            },
            {
              "question": "In counting the numbers from 1 to 99 (inclusive), what is the total number of times that the digit 3 is used?\n\n    Details and assumptions \n    The number 12 uses the digit 1 once and the digit 2 once. \n    The number 111 uses the digit 1 three times.",
              "options": [
                "3",
                "9",
                "10",
                "20"
              ],
              "answer": "20",
              "solution": "Answer: 20"
            },
            {
              "question": "Ian picked 68 distinct integers out of the first 100 positive integers. What is the minimum number of odd integers that Ian must have picked?",
              "options": [
                "50",
                "18",
                "34",
                "51"
              ],
              "answer": "18",
              "solution": "Since there are 50 even integers out of the first 100 positive integers, at most 50 of the distinct integers in  are even. Hence, at least 68 - 50 = 18 integers are odd. It is clear how to create such a set - pick all 50 even integers, and then any 18 odd integers."
            },
            {
              "question": "\\(100\\) students take an exam with two questions a and b. If  \\(66\\) students solved question a,  \\(54\\) students solved question b, and  \\(18\\) students solved neither of the two questions, how many students solved only a?",
              "options": [
                "28",
                "36",
                "38",
                "34"
              ],
              "answer": "28",
              "solution": "Answer: 28\n    \n    Let  \\(A\\) and  \\(B\\) be the sets of students who solved a and b, respectively. Then the number of students who solved at least one question is  \\(\\lvert{A \\cup B}\rvert=100-18=82\\) because  \\(18\\) students out of  \\(100\\) solved neither of the two questions. Hence, the number of students who solved both a and b can be calculated as follows:\n     \\[\begin{aligned} \\lvert{A \\cap B}\rvert &= \\lvert{A}\rvert+\\lvert{B}\rvert-\\lvert{A \\cup B}\rvert \\ &= 66+54-82 \\ &= 38. \\end{aligned} \\]\n    Thus, the number of students who solved only a, or equivalently, who solved a but did not solve b is\n     \\[\begin{aligned} \\lvert{A \\setminus B}\rvert &= \\lvert{A}\rvert-\\lvert{A \\cap B}\rvert \\ &= 66-38 \\ &= 28. \\end{aligned} \\]"
            },
            {
              "question": "Person \"A\" says the truth 60% of the time, and person \"B\" does so 90% of the time. In what percentage of cases are they likely to contradict each other in stating the same fact?",
              "options": [
                "42%",
                "54%",
                "60%",
                "36%"
              ],
              "answer": "42%",
              "solution": "Answer: 42\\%\n     \n     when they both say true the probability is 60*90/100=54;\n\n    When the both say false at same time is 40*10/100=4;\n    So the say always the same fact is 54+4=58\\%;    \n    So the percentage of cases that they contradict each other is 100-58=42\\%"
            }
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "unitName": "Calculus I&II",
      "chapters": [
        {
          "topic": "Limits of Functions",
          "lesson": "In mathematics, the limit of a function is a fundamental concept in calculus and analysis concerning the behavior of that function near a particular input.\nFormal definitions, first devised in the early 19th century, are given below. Informally, a function f assigns an output f(x) to every input x. We say the function has a limit L at an input p: this means f(x) gets closer and closer to L as x moves closer and closer to p. More specifically, when f is applied to any input sufficiently close to p, the output value is forced arbitrarily close to L. On the other hand, if some inputs very close to p are taken to outputs that stay a fixed distance apart, we say the limit does not exist.\nThe notion of a limit has many applications in modern calculus. In particular, the many definitions of continuity employ the limit: roughly, a function is continuous if all of its limits agree with the values of the function. It also appears in the definition of the derivative: in the calculus of one variable, this is the limiting value of the slope of secant lines to the graph of a function.\nSources: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Limit_of_a_function",
          "questions": [
            {
              "question": "Find the value of $$\\lim_{x \\to 3}(x^3 - 9)$$",
              "options": [
                "12",
                "14",
                "16",
                "18"
              ],
              "answer": "18"
            },
            {
              "question": "Which is true of n? $$\\lim_{x \\to 0}\\frac{x^5}{x^n} = 1$$",
              "options": [
                "x < 5",
                "x = 5",
                "x > 5"
              ],
              "answer": "x = 5"
            },
            {
              "question": "When \\(x\\) approaches 10, what does the value of $$\\lim_{x \\to 10}\\frac{x^2-4x+4}{\\left(x-2\\right)^2}?$$",
              "options": [
                "undefined",
                "inf",
                "0",
                "1"
              ],
              "answer": "1"
            },
            {
              "question": "Evaluate $$\\lim_{x \\to -5}\\frac{x^2 -25}{x+5}$$",
              "options": [
                "-5",
                "-10",
                "-15",
                "-25"
              ],
              "answer": "-10"
            },
            {
              "question": "Evaluate $$\\lim_{t \\to 2}\\frac{t^2+3t-4}{t^2-2}$$",
              "options": [
                "5/6",
                "2",
                "7/4",
                "3"
              ],
              "answer": "7/4"
            },
            {
              "question": "Evaluate $$\\lim_{x \\to 0}\\frac{x^2-3x+2}{x^3-2x}$$",
              "options": [
                "2",
                "-inf",
                "-2",
                "inf"
              ],
              "answer": "-inf"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "topic": "Derivatives",
          "lesson": "The derivative of a function of a real variable measures the sensitivity to change of the function value with respect to a change in its argument (input value). Derivatives are a fundamental tool of calculus. For example, the derivative of the position of a moving object with respect to time is the object's velocity: this measures how quickly the position of the object changes when time advances.\nThe derivative of a function of a single variable at a chosen input value, when it exists, is the slope of the tangent line to the graph of the function at that point. The tangent line is the best linear approximation of the function near that input value. For this reason, the derivative is often described as the \"instantaneous rate of change\", the ratio of the instantaneous change in the dependent variable to that of the independent variable.\nDerivatives may be generalized to functions of several real variables. In this generalization, the derivative is reinterpreted as a linear transformation whose graph is (after an appropriate translation) the best linear approximation to the graph of the original function. The Jacobian matrix is the matrix that represents this linear transformation with respect to the basis given by the choice of independent and dependent variables. It can be calculated in terms of the partial derivatives with respect to the independent variables. For a real-valued function of several variables, the Jacobian matrix reduces to the gradient vector.\nSources: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Derivative",
          "questions": [
            {
              "question": "Let $$f(x) = 2x^3 + 4x^2 - 5x + 7$$ What is the value of \\(f'(2)\\)?",
              "options": [
                "25",
                "35",
                "45",
                "55"
              ],
              "answer": "35"
            },
            {
              "question": "Let n be a real number and $$f(x) = x^n + x^(-n)$$ What is the value of \\(f'(1)\\)?",
              "options": [
                "0",
                "1",
                "-1",
                "undefined"
              ],
              "answer": "0"
            },
            {
              "question": "If \\(f'(x)\\) = \\(g'(x)\\) for all real numbers \\(x\\) then \\(f(x)\\) = \\(g(x)\\) for all real numbers \\(x\\). True or False?",
              "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
              ],
              "answer": "False"
            },
            {
              "question": "What is the value of $$\\lim_{h \\to 0}\\frac{(5+h)^2 - 5^2}{h}?$$",
              "options": [
                "0",
                "5",
                "10",
                "15"
              ],
              "answer": "10"
            },
            {
              "question": "Let $$f(x) = \\frac{x^7 + x}{x^4}$$ What is the value of \\(f'(1)\\)?",
              "options": [
                "-2",
                "-1",
                "0",
                "1"
              ],
              "answer": "0"
            },
            {
              "question": "If \\(f(x)\\) and \\(g(x)\\) are linear function such that \\(f'(2) = 8\\) and \\(g'(3) = 6\\), what is the value of \\(f'(5) + f'(6)\\)?",
              "options": [
                "6",
                "8",
                "12",
                "14"
              ],
              "answer": "14"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "topic": "Integrals",
          "lesson": "In mathematics, an integral assigns numbers to functions in a way that can describe displacement, area, volume, and other concepts that arise by combining infinitesimal data. Integration is one of the two main operations of calculus, with its inverse, differentiation, being the other. Given a function f of a real variable x and an interval [a, b] of the real line, the definite integral\n$$\\int _{a}^{b}\\!f(x)\\,dx$$\nis defined informally as the signed area of the region in the xy-plane that is bounded by the graph of f, the x-axis and the vertical lines x = a and x = b. The area above the x-axis adds to the total and that below the x-axis subtracts from the total.\nRoughly speaking, the operation of integration is the reverse of differentiation. For this reason, the term integral may also refer to the related notion of the antiderivative, a function F whose derivative is the given function f. In this case, it is called an indefinite integral and is written:\n$$F(x)=\\int f(x)\\,dx.$$\nThe integrals discussed in this article are those termed definite integrals. It is the fundamental theorem of calculus that connects differentiation with the definite integral: if f is a continuous real-valued function defined on a closed interval [a, b], then, once an antiderivative F of f is known, the definite integral of f over that interval is given by\n$$\\int _{a}^{b}\\!f(x)\\,dx=F(b)-F(a).$$\nThe principles of integration were formulated independently by Isaac Newton and Gottfried Leibniz in the late 17th century, who thought of the integral as an infinite sum of rectangles of infinitesimal width. A rigorous mathematical definition of the integral was given by Bernhard Riemann. It is based on a limiting procedure which approximates the area of a curvilinear region by breaking the region into thin vertical slabs. Beginning in the nineteenth century, more sophisticated notions of integrals began to appear, where the type of the function as well as the domain over which the integration is performed has been generalised. A line integral is defined for functions of two or three variables, and the interval of integration [a, b] is replaced by a certain curve connecting two points on the plane or in the space. In a surface integral, the curve is replaced by a piece of a surface in the three-dimensional space.\nSources: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Integral",
          "questions": [
            {
              "question": "If \\(\\int_0^1 f(x)\\, dx = 1\\), what is the value of $$\\int_0^1 -2 f(x)\\, dx ?$$",
              "options": [
                "-2",
                "-1",
                "0",
                "1"
              ],
              "answer": "-2"
            },
            {
              "question": "Suppose \\(\\int_1^2 f(x)\\, dx = 3\\) and \\(\\int_2^3 f(x)\\, dx = 5\\). Find the correct value of $$\\int_0^1 2 f(x) \\, dx$$",
              "options": [
                "2",
                "4",
                "6",
                "8"
              ],
              "answer": "8"
            },
            {
              "question": "Let \\(\\int_0^1 f(x)\\, dx = 2\\) and  \\(\\int_0^1 g(x)\\, dx = 3\\). Choose the correct answer for $$\\int_0^1 \\left(5f(x) + 7g(x)\\right)\\, dx$$" ,
              "options": [
                "21",
                "25",
                "27",
                "31"
              ],
              "answer": "31"
            },
            {
              "question": "Evaluate $$\\int_0^1 (3x^2 + 2x + 5) \\, dx$$",
              "options": [
                "3",
                "5",
                "7",
                "9"
              ],
              "answer": "7"
            },
            {
              "question": "If $$\\int_{0}^{K} x dx =8$$. Assume \\(K\\) > 0, what is the value of \\(K\\)?",
              "options": [
                "2",
                "4",
                "6",
                "8"
              ],
              "answer": "4"
            },
            {
              "question": "Let \\(\\int_0^{5} f(x)\\, dx = 10\\) and  \\(\\int_0^{2} f(x)\\, dx = 5\\). Find \\( \\int_2^{3} f(x)\\, dx \\)",
              "options": [
                "3",
                "5",
                "7",
                "9"
              ],
              "answer": "5"
            }
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "unitName": "Linear Algebra",
      "chapters": [
        {
          "topic": "Determinant Computations",
          "lesson": "In linear algebra, the determinant is a useful value that can be computed from the elements of a square matrix. The determinant of a matrix A is denoted det(A), detA , or |A|. It can be viewed as the scaling factor of the transformation described by the matrix.\nIn the case of a 2 × 2 matrix, the specific formula for the determinant: $$ |A| = \\begin{vmatrix} a&b\\\\c&d \\end{vmatrix} = ad-bc. $$ Each determinant of a 2 × 2 matrix in this equation is called a \"minor\" of the matrix A. The same sort of procedure can be used to find the determinant of a 4 × 4 matrix, the determinant of a 5 × 5 matrix, and so forth.\nDeterminants occur throughout mathematics. For example, a matrix is often used to represent the coefficients in a system of linear equations, and the determinant can be used to solve those equations, although more efficient techniques are actually used, some of which are determinant-revealing and consist of computationally effective ways of computing the determinant itself. The use of determinants in calculus includes the Jacobian determinant in the change of variables rule for integrals of functions of several variables. Determinants are also used to define the characteristic polynomial of a matrix, which is essential for eigenvalue problems in linear algebra. In analytical geometry, determinants express the signed n-dimensional volumes of n-dimensional parallelepipeds. Sometimes, determinants are used merely as a compact notation for expressions that would otherwise be unwieldy to write down.\nWhen the entries of the matrix are taken from a field (like the real or complex numbers), it can be proven that any matrix has a unique inverse if and only if its determinant is nonzero. Various other theorems can be proved as well, including that the determinant of a product of matrices is always equal to the product of determinants; and, the determinant of a Hermitian matrix is always real. \n Sources: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Determinant",
          "questions": [
            {
              "question": "Compute the determinant of the following matrix $$A = \\left( \\begin{bmatrix} 3&5\\\\ -2& 4\\end{bmatrix} \\right)$$",
              "options": [
                "8",
                "17",
                "22",
                "35"
              ],
              "answer": "22",
              "solution": "det(A) = 22 because(3)(4)-(5)(-2) = 12 + 10 = 22."
            },
            {
              "question": "Without evaluating, give the reason why the determinant of the following matrix is equal to zero $$A = \\left( \\begin{bmatrix} 0& 0& 0& 0\\\\ 1& 2& 0& 0\\\\ 0& 4& 3& 0\\\\ 1& 2& 3& 8\\end{bmatrix} \\right)$$ ",
              "options": [
                "A has two identical rows (columns)",
                "one row(column) is a multiple of another",
                "rows (column) of zeros"
              ],
              "answer": "rows (column) of zeros",
              "solution": "It consist a row of zeros so the answer will be a muliple of zeros."
            },
            {
              "question": "Compute the determinant of the following matrix $$A = \\left( \\begin{bmatrix} 5& 7& 2& -1\\\\ 0& 2& 4& 0\\\\ 0& 0& 3& 1\\\\ 0& 0& 0& 8\\end{bmatrix} \\right)$$",
              "options": [
                "300",
                "120",
                "72",
                "240"
              ],
              "answer": "240",
              "solution": "det(A) = 240 since A is a triangular matrix, it det(A) will be the product if the entries on the main diagonal."
            },
            {
              "question": "Compute the minor of the following matrix $$A = \\left( \\begin{bmatrix} 4& -1& 1& 6\\\\ 0& 0& -3& 3\\\\ 4& 1& 0& 14\\\\ 4& 1& 3& 2\\end{bmatrix} \\right)$$ What is M13?",
              "options": [
                "0",
                "1",
                "2",
                "7"
              ],
              "answer": "0"
            },
            {
              "question": "Find all values of x for which det(A) = 0 $$A = \\left( \\begin{bmatrix} x-1 & 0 \\\\ 2& x+1 \\end{bmatrix} \\right)$$",
              "options": [
                "1",
                "-1",
                "1 and -1",
                "none of above"
              ],
              "answer": "1 and -1",
              "solution": "Both 1 and -1 works. Since det(A)= (x + 1)(x - 1), so det(A) = 0 if and only if x = 1 or x = -1."
            },
            {
              "question": "What is the maximum number of zeroes that a 3 by 3 matrix can have without having a zero determinant?",
              "options": [
                "3",
                "4",
                "5",
                "6"
              ],
              "answer": "6",
              "solution": "the matrix can have at most 6 zeros without determinant being 0. we can show by letting the matrix be a diagonal matrix with nonzero diagonal entries."
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "topic": "Matrix Operations",
          "lesson": "In mathematics, a matrix (plural matrices) is a rectangular array of numbers, symbols, or expressions, arranged in rows and columns.For example, the dimensions of the matrix below are 2 × 3 (read \"two by three\"), because there are two rows and three columns:\n $$ \\begin{bmatrix}1&9&-13\\\\20&5&-6\\end{bmatrix} $$.\nThe individual items in an m × n matrix A, often denoted by ai,j, where max i = m and max j = n, are called its elements or entries. Provided that they have the same size (each matrix has the same number of rows and the same number of columns as the other), two matrices can be added or subtracted element by element (see Conformable matrix). The rule for matrix multiplication, however, is that two matrices can be multiplied only when the number of columns in the first equals the number of rows in the second (i.e., the inner dimensions are the same, n for Am,n × Bn,p). Any matrix can be multiplied element-wise by a scalar from its associated field. A major application of matrices is to represent linear transformations, that is, generalizations of linear functions such as f(x) = 4x. For example, the rotation of vectors in three-dimensional space is a linear transformation, which can be represented by a rotation matrix R: if v is a column vector (a matrix with only one column) describing the position of a point in space, the product Rv is a column vector describing the position of that point after a rotation. The product of two transformation matrices is a matrix that represents the composition of two linear transformations. Another application of matrices is in the solution of systems of linear equations. If the matrix is square, it is possible to deduce some of its properties by computing its determinant. For example, a square matrix has an inverse if and only if its determinant is not zero. Insight into the geometry of a linear transformation is obtainable (along with other information) from the matrix's eigenvalues and eigenvectors.\n Sources: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matrix_(mathematics)",
          "questions": [
            {
              "question": "Suppose A is a 3 by 4 matrix and B is a 4 by 2 matrix.Describe the dimension of AB.",
              "options": [
                "3x4",
                "4x2",
                "3x2",
                "4x4"
              ],
              "answer": "3x2"
            },
            {
              "question": "The following is a 5 by 4 matrix $$A = \\left( \\begin{bmatrix} 5 & 4& 2 & 1 \\\\ 0 & 2& 0 & 1\\\\ 7 & 5& 8 & 2\\\\ 4 & 6& 0 & 0\\\\ 8 & 9& 6 & 5 \\end{bmatrix} \\right)$$ What is the second column of A?",
              "options": [
                "5 0 7 4 8",
                "4 2 5 6 9",
                "2 0 8 0 6",
                "1 1 2 0 5"
              ],
              "answer": "4 2 5 6 9"
            },
            {
              "question": "The following are 2 by 2 matrices $$A = \\left( \\begin{bmatrix} 3&2\\\\ 6&1 \\end{bmatrix} \\right)$$ \n $$B = \\left( \\begin{bmatrix} 7&1\\\\ 4&0 \\end{bmatrix} \\right)$$ Compute the sum of A + B.",
              "options": [
                "10 3 | 10 1",
                "12 | 11",
                "undefined"
              ],
              "answer": "10 3 | 10 1"
            },
            {
              "question": "The following are 2 by 2 matrices $$A = \\left( \\begin{bmatrix} 3&2\\\\ 6&1 \\end{bmatrix} \\right)$$ \n $$B = \\left( \\begin{bmatrix} 7&1\\\\ 4&0 \\end{bmatrix} \\right)$$ Compute the product of AB.",
              "options": [
                "21 2 | 24 0",
                "29 3 | 46 6",
                "10 3 | 10 1",
                "undefined"
              ],
              "answer": "29 3 |46 6"
            },
            {
              "question": "Consider the following matrices $$A = \\left( \\begin{bmatrix} 5 & 4& 2 & 1 \\\\ 0 & 2& 0 & 1\\\\ 7 & 5& 8 & 2\\\\ 4 & 6& 0 & 0\\\\ 8 & 9& 6 & 5 \\end{bmatrix} \\right)$$ \n $$B = \\left( \\begin{bmatrix} 12\\\\ 11 \\end{bmatrix} \\right)$$ Compute the product of AB.",
              "options": [
                "3 100 | 25 17",
                "45 83 | 98 77",
                "10 34 | 11 24",
                "undefined"
              ],
              "answer": "undefined"
            },
            {
              "question": "Suppose A is a 3 by 4 matrix and B is a 3 by 4 matrix. Describe the dimension of AB.",
              "options": [
                "3x4",
                "4x2",
                "3x2",
                "undefined"
              ],
              "answer": "undefined"
            }
          ]
        },
        {
          "topic": "Vectors and Linear Equation",
          "lesson": "A linear equation is an algebraic equation in which each term is either a constant or the product of a constant and (the first power of) a single variable (however, different variables may occur in different terms). A simple example of a linear equation with only one variable, x, may be written in the form: ax + b = 0, where a and b are constants and a ≠ 0. The constants may be numbers, parameters, or even non-linear functions of parameters, and the distinction between variables and parameters may depend on the problem (for an example, see linear regression).\nLinear equations can have one or more variables. An example of a linear equation with three variables, x, y, and z, is given by: ax + by + cz + d = 0, where a, b, c, and d are constants and a, b, and c are non-zero. Linear equations occur frequently in most subareas of mathematics and especially in applied mathematics. While they arise quite naturally when modeling many phenomena, they are particularly useful since many non-linear equations may be reduced to linear equations by assuming that quantities of interest vary to only a small extent from some \"background\" state. An equation is linear if the sum of the exponents of the variables of each term is one.\nEquations with exponents greater than one are non-linear. An example of a non-linear equation of two variables is axy + b = 0, where a and b are constants and a ≠ 0. It has two variables, x and y, and is non-linear because the sum of the exponents of the variables in the first term, axy, is two.\nThis article considers the case of a single equation for which one searches the real solutions. All its content applies for complex solutions and, more generally for linear equations with coefficients and solutions in any field. \n Sources: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linear_equation",
          "questions": [
            {
              "question": "Compute the dot product of u . v when \\( u = (3, 1, 4) \\) and \\( v = (2, 2, 4) \\)",
              "options": [
                "(5, 3, 8)",
                "(6, 2, 12)",
                "(8, 8)",
                "(12, 16)"
              ],
              "answer": "(6, 2, 12)"
            },
            {
              "question": "The set of all points such that \\( x = x0 + tv \\), represents the line through x0 that is parallel to v and the varaible t is called a parameter. \n Question: what if \\( x0 = 0 \\)?",
              "options": [
                "plane including origin",
                "a point at the origin ",
                "line passing through the origin"
              ],
              "answer": "line passing through the origin"
            },
            {
              "question": "Match the properties of vectors \\( a) u + v = v + u \\) \n \\( b) (u + v) + w = u + (v + w) \\) \n \\( c) u + 0 = u \\) \n1) zero identity \n2) associative law \n3) commutative law" ,
              "options": [
                "a) = 2) ,b) = 1), c) = 3)",
                "a) = 3), b) = 2), c) = 1)",
                "a) = 3), b) = 1), c) = 2)",
                "a) = 2), b) = 3), c) = 1)"
              ],
              "answer": "a) = 3), b) = 1), c) = 2)"
            },
            {
              "question": "Find the augmented matrix for the linear system \\( x1 = 1 \\), \\( x2 = 2 \\), \\( x3 = 3 \\)",
              "options": [
                "1 0 0 1 | 0 1 0 2 | 0 0 1 3",
                "1 0 0 | 0 2 0 | 0 0 3",
                "1 0 0 | 0 1 0 | 0 0 1"
              ],
              "answer": "1 0 0 1 | 0 1 0 2 | 0 0 1 3"
            },
            {
              "question": "Fill in the blank. If a linear system has [  ] solution, its called [ ].",
              "options": [
                "zero, consistent",
                "at least one, consistent",
                "at least one, inconsistent",
                "infinite, in consistent"
              ],
              "answer": "at least one, inconsistent"
            },
            {
              "question": "What does a linear equation in (a) \\( R^{2} \\) and (b) \\( R^{3} \\) represents?",
              "options": [
                "plane, line",
                "line, plane",
                "dot, line",
                "line, dot"
              ],
              "answer": "line, plane"
            }
          ]
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}
